(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T09:52:53.075539",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
よっ、聞いてください！
Hey, listen up!
誇り高きアイドル！
A proud idol!
私のこと知ってますか?
Do you know who I am?
可愛く見えてますか?
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
What do you think of my singing?
上手に歌えてますか?
Am I singing well?
衣装とかメイクとか
My outfit and makeup,
可愛く見えてますか?
Do I look cute wearing them?
振付とかファンサとかも
My dancing and fanservice too,
喜んでもらえますか?
Do they make you happy?
手は冷たくなって足は震える
My hands get cold and my legs shake,
それでも戦いたい
but even so, I want to fight
アイドルだから
because I'm an idol!
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate people who make fun of me,
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down on too.
“アイドルなんとか”という言葉を
Words like "some kind of idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
don't say them without even seeing me!
頑張りを当然と言うな
Don't take my hard work for granted,
イメージとか強制するな
don't force an image on me.
“アイドルなんとか”という言葉はこの世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "some kind of idol" are what I hate most in this world!
愛されたいとかという言葉は 見てもいないくせに言うな
Don't talk about wanting to be loved when you don't even look at me.
ステージに立つというなら
If you're going to stand on stage,
イメージと違うせいで 愛されたいとかいう言葉は
because it's not the image you wanted...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
I hate it more than anything in this world!
プライベート見えないから 分からないと思います
Since my private life is invisible, you probably don't know,
性格とか悪い方です 騙しちゃってますか？
my personality is pretty bad, am I deceiving you?
でも本気です 本気なんです ありのままの私を
But I'm serious, I really am! The real me just as I am,
好きになって推して下さい それってワガママですか？
please love and support me. Is that too selfish?
キミがいくない 全部わかってる
You think it's no good, I understand it all,
それでも疲れてたい アイドルだから
but I still want to be exhausted, because I'm an idol.
キミがいうヤツは嫌いだ 今だけバカも嫌いだ
I hate the guys you talk about, I hate being called a fool right now,
こんな男と生きる言葉は 軽々しく口にするな
don't casually say words about living with a man like this!
勝手に限界決めるな 笑い者になってすんな
Don't decide my limit on your own, don't make me a laughingstock!
アイドルなんかという言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most in this world!
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol!
応援してなければ 活動できない 好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
If you don't support me I can't be active, can't live only doing what I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし 恩返しできる日まで待ってて！
I'm supposed to give you energy, but I just keep receiving it. Wait until the day I can repay you!
風邪がへえても 飽きられちゃっても それでも笑っていたい アイドルだから
Even if the wind changes, even if people get tired of me, I still want to smile because I'm an idol!
熱いファンの愛があって スタッフさんの愛があって いつも家族の愛があって 生きてる！上がれ！
With the love of passionate fans, staff, and family always, I'm alive! Let's go up!
ばかり続ける奴は嫌いだ 尽くされるのも嫌いだ アイドルなんかという言葉は 見てもいないくせに言うな
I hate guys who keep taking, I hate being pampered too. Don't say "just an idol" when you don't even look!
頑張りも当然と言うな イメージと強制するな
Don't call my hard work natural, don't force your image on me!
アイドルなんかという言葉は この世で一番大嫌いだ
Words like "just an idol" are what I hate most in this world!
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol!
えっ、待ってこれ大空警察じゃん！こっちです！え、こっちで？
Eh, wait, isn't this Oozora Police?! Over here! Eh, over here?
え、こっちで違法なアイドルライブが行われてます！
Eh, an illegal idol live is being held over here!
え？大空警察です！
Huh? Oozora Police here!
アイドルが公の場で笑顔を振りまく恋は禁止だ！言います、解散しなさい！
Idols spreading smiles in public is forbidden by love! I say, disband!
え、ちょ、どういうこと？解散って？いや、違法なアイドルライブって！
Eh, wait, what do you mean? Disband? No, illegal idol live?!
いやいや、アイドルが違法ってどういうこと？そんなの聞いたことないよ！とにかく逃げなきゃ！
No no, how is an idol illegal? I've never heard of that! Anyway, we gotta run!
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
尾丸ポルカ 2周年記念公演
[Title: Omaru Polka 2nd Anniversary Performance]
ようやく逃げてこられた。なに？んなの？
We finally managed to escape. What? What is this?
違法なアイドルライブとか言ってたくせに、や、しかも大空警察まで来てたし、えー！？
Saying it was an illegal idol live, and even Oozora Police came, eh—?!
え？ これからどうなっちゃうの？
Huh? What's going to happen to me now?
アイドルライブってできるのかな？
Can I really do an idol live show?
でも、アイドルはそんなことしないとか違法とか言ってたし、えーーやだっ！
But they said idols don't do that, or that it's illegal... No way!
私まだいっぱいうたいたい歌あるし、アイドルのライブやりたいし！
I still have so many songs I want to sing, and I want to do idol live shows!
それに、ファンのみなさんだって、いっぱい想い届けたいから……そんなの、おかしいでしょ！
Besides, I want to deliver my feelings to all my fans... That doesn't make sense!
あのね 私ルーザーガール
Hey, I'm a loser girl.
だって 開き直るしか ないじゃん
Because I have no choice but to start over.
劣等感だって悪くはないけど今はね
Inferiority complexes aren't necessarily bad, but right now...
負けられないのよ
I can't afford to lose.
ここで勝てなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I can't win here, my life will stop forever.
じゃあ私にできることは何？
So what is it that I can do?
誰か教えてそれじゃダメなの？って
Someone tell me, is that no good?
一生劣等ルーザーガール
A lifelong inferior loser girl.
あの子みたいになりたくてあの子みたいになれなくて
Wanting to be like that girl, but unable to be like her,
楽しくて満たされてもういいやって終わるだけ
Being happy and satisfied, just ending with a "that's enough."
最初ってそんなもんで十分に幸せで
The beginning is just like that, perfectly happy,
でもいつだか足りなくてもういいやって止まれない
But somehow it's never enough, and I can't stop.
気づいた時私は何者かになりたくて
When I realized it, I wanted to become somebody,
だんだん周りが見えてきたんだ
And gradually my surroundings started coming into view.
ライバルがたくさんね
There are so many rivals, you see.
だんだん私の立場も見えて大したことないね
Gradually my own position became clear, and I'm nothing special.
劣等感だって悪くはないスパイスなんだけど
An inferiority complex isn't a bad spice, but...
今はね痛いだけなのよ
Right now, it just hurts.
ここで立たなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I don't stand here, my life will stop forever.
じゃあ私にできることは何？
So what is it that I can do?
努力したけどそれじゃダメなの？って
I made an effort, but is that no good?
一生劣等ルーザーガール
A lifelong inferior loser girl.
あの子みたいになりたくてあの子みたいになれなくて
Wanting to be like that girl, but unable to be like her,
あのね 私ルーザーガール
Hey, I'm a loser girl.
待って 置いてかないでよなんて
Wait, don't leave me behind, or so I say.
あのね 私ルーザーガール
Hey, I'm a loser girl.
だって 開き直るしか ないじゃん
Because I have no choice but to start over.
劣等感だって悪くはないけど 今はね
Inferiority complexes aren't necessarily bad, but right now...
生き抜くためなのよ
It's in order to survive.
ここで魅せなきゃもう人生一生止まって
If I don't show my charm here, my life will stop forever.
じゃあ私にできることは何？
So what is it that I can do?
誰か教えてそれじゃダメなの？って
Someone tell me, is that no good?
一生劣等ルーザーガール
A lifelong inferior loser girl.
あの子みたいになりたくて
Wanting to be like that girl,
あの子みたいになれなくて
But unable to be like her.
この世界のトップアイドルとの出会い
[Title: Encounter with the Top Idols of This World]
ひよこの声がしたの、こっちの方かな？
I heard a chick's voice. Is it this way?
なんかすっごい盛り上がってたけど……
It was getting so hyped up, though...
もしかして、アイドルライブ！？
Could this be... an idol live show?!
あっ！ あれっ！？ あっ、やっぱり！
Ah! Huh?! Ah, I knew it!
アイドルライブじゃん！
It's an idol live show!
ねぇ、なんでそんな笑ってないの？
Hey, why aren't you smiling?
え、やっぱりさ、おかしいよね？違法なアイドルライブなんて！
Wait, seriously, isn't that weird? An illegal idol live show?!
今のアイドルってどうなっちゃったの？
What has happened to idols nowadays?
ねぇ、もっとキラキラしてるアイドルにポルカもう一回なりたいよ！どうすればいいの？
Hey, I want to become a sparkling idol once again, Polka does! What should I do?
駄目なのだよ。
That won't do, nano.
アイドルは笑顔なんて見せないのだ。
Idols never show their smiles, nano.
アイドルはみんなの手が届かない、
Idols are out of everyone's reach—
神聖で素晴らしいもの。
A sacred and wonderful existence.
あなたもこうなりたいなら、頑張るしかないね。
If you want to become like this too, you have no choice but to work hard.
えーー！？いやいやいや、やっぱりそんなのおかしいって！それにさ……
Eh—?! No way, no way, that's still weird! Besides...
こんなこと望んでるのかな
Is this really what I wished for?
ザイン君？
Zain-kun?
ちょっと待って
Wait a second!
ザイン君！
Zain-kun!
待って
Wait!
ねえ
Hey!
キミ、ザイン君だよね？
You're Zain-kun, right?
あれ？ どこいっちゃった？
Huh? Where'd he go?
アタシどうしたんだっけ？
What happened to me again?
ここどこだっけ？
Where am I?
あれ？
Huh?
わかんないや
I don't know.
アリーナなのに
Even though it's an arena,
アリーナみたいじゃない、そんな気がするし
it doesn't feel like an arena... or at least it feels that way.
ザイン君も夢？
Is Zain-kun a dream too?
何が正しいの？
What is right?
アイドルって何？
What is an idol?
笑うことがアイドルじゃないの？
Isn't an idol supposed to smile?
アイドルって笑わせてで、笑ってもらって笑顔を振りまいてさ……
Idols make you laugh, make you smile, shower you with smiles...
そうじゃないんだ、いまは
That's not how it is right now.
もう、そっか
Oh right...
こんな世界、おかしいよ
A world like this is crazy!
全部壊れちゃえばいいのに
Everything should just break apart.
Hello! Hello! Everyone
まもなく On Stage
Coming soon On Stage
Lie Life 自己暗示さ
Lie Life, autosuggestion,
さあ…始めよう。
now... let's begin.
「ようこそParty Night」誰かが語る
"Welcome to Party Night," someone whispers.
連日満員御礼 どうぞご贔屓に
Packed houses every day, please treat us favorably.
「待ってたShow Time」誰かが語る
"Waiting for Show Time," someone whispers,
どうでもいいような 顔を見せてよね
show me a face that looks like it doesn't even matter.
はぁ… 偶像捏造炎上、並べたなら一攫千金？
Ah... Fabricated idols and online controversy—line them up for quick riches?
ふざけちゃいませんか？ 今辿り着いた憧れの世界
Aren't you messing around? The world of longing I've finally reached
ここはまるでペテン師の楽園
is like a paradise for swindlers.
吐き気を飲み込む
Swallowing down the nausea.
前略 幕が開けたそのオノマトペ
Dearly, the onomatopoeia when the curtain rose,
着飾る人形はピエロに口づけを
the dressing doll gives a kiss to the pierrot.
本日大団円 脚本が笑う
Today's grand finale, the script laughs.
騙されてくれる貴方達と アタシ今ここで何をしてる？
With all of you who let yourselves be fooled, what am I doing right here?
耳をつんざく拍手喝采
Deafening applause and cheers,
サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
even a monkey can become human if you flatter it.
耳をつんざく拍手喝采
Deafening applause and cheers,
サルもおだてればヒトにもなれる
even a monkey can become human if you flatter it.
フォーカスされた日常
Focused everyday life,
引き金を抱いて心中するように
holding the trigger as if committing a double suicide.
一回、二回、三回 嘘を重ねて
Once, twice, thrice, piling up lies,
十回、千回、億回 瞳を逸して
ten times, a thousand times, a hundred million times, looking away.
あれ？なんだっけかな アタシは誰？
Huh? What was it again? Who am I?
もうウンザリした仮面舞踏会 とりどめのないワルツでお迎え
Already sick of this masquerade, greeted by a rambling waltz.
贋作の中 嘲てみてよ 嗤ってみてよ
Inside the forgery, mock me, laugh at me.
アタシの世界はグルグルクルクルぐるぐる回ってく
My world spins round and round and round in circles.
贋作の中 嘲てみてよ 嗤ってみてよ
Inside the forgery, mock me, laugh at me.
アタシの世界はグルグルクルクルぐるぐる回ってく
My world spins round and round and round in circles.
前略 幕が開けたそのオノマトペ
Dearly, the onomatopoeia when the curtain rose,
群がる人形はダリアの花束を
the swarming dolls holding a bouquet of dahlias.
選んでくれた服を着て 踊りましょう
Let's dance wearing the clothes you chose for me.
騙されてくれる貴方達と いいよもう
With all of you who let yourselves be fooled—fine, whatever,
これが好きだっただけだろ？
this is all you liked, right?
振り落とせ ペルソナを
Shake it off, your persona.
とっくに終わった劇は
The play that ended long ago
悲劇と化してなお 今日も普通に楽しかったよ
has turned into a tragedy, yet today was just normally fun.
(今日も普通に楽しかったよ)
(Today was just normally fun)
さあ 刮目してくれよ
Now, keep your eyes wide open.
本当の僕はアタシじゃないから
Because the real me is not me.
アタシじゃないから
Because it's not me,
今日も普通に楽しかったよ
Today was normally fun too.
戦略的幕引きが訪れたその面会って
That strategic curtain call and meeting...
着せ替え人形と輪廻のアンコール
A dress-up doll and an encore of reincarnation.
本日大団円 劇薬本音を笑う
Today's grand finale, laughing at dangerous true feelings.
どうしようもないよな?!
There's nothing we can do, right?!
ああ、ああ、
Ah, ah...
どこの誰でもいい「調子に乗るなよ」とただ一回言ってくれ
Anyone at all, just say "don't get full of yourself" once.
そういや群々も散々言ってたな
Come to think of it, crowds said that a lot too.
「もう後戻りは叶わない」と
"There's no turning back now."
気付けばそこには一人で
Before I knew it, I was all alone there.
ずららぬららずららぬららめくるるりら めざめびらる
Zurara nurara, turning pages and waking up...
ずららぬららてんでるらり ずららぬららびんどみーれ
Zurara nurara, finding you there...
どうせフィクションの物語
After all, it's a fictional story.
そう、どうせフィクションの物語だからね。
Yeah, after all, it's a fictional story, right?
そう、フィクションだけに！フィクション！
Yeah, just fiction! Fiction!
またお前ら変なことしてる。
You guys are doing weird things again.
のみー！
Nomi!
はいはい、また遊びに行こうね！うん、うん、ありがとう。涙だけでそんなの。
Yes, yes, let's go play again! Yep, yep, thanks. Shedding tears over just that...
え？声はポルカ先輩のこと大好きですよ！
Eh? We love Polka-senpai so much!
こよりも？もっと自信持って！一緒にアイドル活動続けましょう！
Koyori too? Have more confidence! Let's keep up our idol activities together!
わかった。２人がそう言ってくれるなら私、もうちょっと頑張れるかも。よし！
I see. If the two of you say that, maybe I can try a little harder. Alright!
私は頑張って変えていく、この世界を！
I'll do my best to change this world!
決意
Determination
太陽が地平線に呑み込まれるのを眺めていた
I was watching the sun get swallowed by the horizon.
まぶたを閉じればわたしも消してしまえるような気がしたのに
Even though I felt like closing my eyes could make even me disappear,
くだらない白昼夢 終止符を打つ 生活の着信音
A pointless daydream, striking a period, the ringtone of daily life.
ばかになった蛇口 栓のない心 鏡は曇っている
A faucet gone stupid, a heart without a plug, the mirror is clouded.
脱ぎ捨てた服さえよそよそしい
Even the clothes I cast off feel distant and polite.
ここは底なしの海 悲しくはない 苦しくもない 寂しくもない
This is a bottomless sea. It's not sad, it's not painful, it's not lonely.
悲しくない苦しくない寂しくない悲しくない苦しくない寂しくないもううるさいな
Not sad, not painful, not lonely, not sad, not painful, not lonely, oh, shut up!
うおおおおどこまでも沈む 神さまでさえ見つけられないくらい
Ooh, sinking endlessly, to a depth where even God cannot find me.
深く深く沈んでいく なまぬるいバスタブ
Sinking deeper and deeper into a lukewarm bathtub.
うおおおー
Ooh—
乾いたタイルに響くレクイエム
A requiem echoing on the dry tiles.
せかいがわたしだけを置いていく
The world is leaving only me behind.
泡になってなくなるなんてうつつしい終わりはきっとこない
An ephemeral ending like turning into bubbles will surely never come,
魂ひとつすらままならないし せかいは不完全で果てがないもの
even a single soul won't stay put, and the world is incomplete and endless.
濡れて張り付いた孤独が冷え切って いつまでもわたしをがんじがらめにしている
The wet, clinging loneliness grows ice-cold, binding me tightly forever.
この薄暗い胎にたずんだ 永遠の終わらせ方を知らないまま
Linger in this dim womb, without knowing how to end eternity.
揺らいでは夜光虫 水面は遠く 静寂と赤信号 ハイでショートしている 帰れないどこも私が狂っている？
Flickering fireflies, the water's surface far away, silence and a red traffic light. High and shorting out, nowhere to return to—am I going crazy?
気が狂っている 時間の中
In the middle of time going crazy
体が離れていく
My body is drifting away
なにも感じたくない、もう
I don't want to feel anything anymore
うおおおお、どこまでも落ちる
Uoooooh, falling endlessly
朝焼けでさえ照らしきれないように
So that even the morning glow cannot fully illuminate
暗く、暗く溺れていく
Drowning deeper and deeper in the dark
なまぬるい霊柩
A lukewarm hearse
一ドル銀貨の月さえ見離すエヴァーブルー
An Ever-Blue where even the one-dollar silver coin moon abandons us
染まっては続くフューネラル
A funeral that continues, stained in Ever-Blue
乾いた夜更けに燃えるレクイエム
A requiem burning in the parched late night
世界がわたしだけを置いていく
The world leaves only me behind
皆さん、私が今期のトップアイドルに選ばれました
Everyone, I have been chosen as this season's top idol
尾丸ポルカと申します
My name is Omaru Polka
私がこの座に選ばれたからには
Now that I have been chosen for this seat
この現上のくさったアイドルをぶっ壊し！
I'm going to smash this rotten excuse for an idol status quo!
新しくピカピカと輝いたアイドル、取り戻してやるかんな！
I'll take back a brand new, sparkling idol!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
ついてこいよ！
Follow me!
もうステージは始まってんだぜ！
The stage has already begun!
おら、行くぞ！
Hey, let's go!
これがアイドルだ！
This is an idol!
最強のポルカになる！
I'll become the strongest Polka!
最強チックポルカ！
The ultimate chic Polka!
お前ら見とけよ！
You guys better watch!
アクセスようこそ 朝昼夜もなく
Welcome to access, day and night without rest
会いに来てくれてうれしい 私も実は待ってた
Happy you came to see me, actually I was waiting too
今日のおあれこれ キミと共有して
Sharing today's this and that with you
おかえりも聞いてきくも 自由な時代だもん
Welcoming you back, listening... it's a free era after all
主張強めだとか 意識高めだとか
Saying my claims are strong, or my awareness is high
お天気次第とか 冴えない言い訳より
Rather than lame excuses like it depends on the weather
たのしい至上主義 認めていきたい
I want to embrace a fun-supremacy philosophy
ご賛同ありがとう これがわたしの流儀
Thanks for your agreement, this is my way
カンチガイされたら それはやっぱ負け込むよ
If you misunderstand, you'll end up losing
キミのことが好きだし ペチャンコポルカ
Because I like you, crushed Polka
歩み寄ってみたりも ちょっとした情緒不安定？
Trying to compromise, or a bit emotionally unstable?
ハートレベルアップしちゃう ムテキナポルカ
My heart level goes up, invincible Polka
そういう距離感 今時っぽいのか
This kind of distance, is it modern?
家族とか友達よりも近く感じることもあるし
Sometimes feeling closer than family or friends
急に音信不通する時があっても
Even if I suddenly go out of touch
いつだって戻ってこれる遊び場っていいよね
It's nice to have a playground where you can always return
一過性って言わないで 永遠って聞かないで
Don't call it a phase, don't ask about eternity
自分たち次第で 未来も変えられる
Depending on ourselves, we can change the future too
たのしい至上主義 極めていくから
Because we'll master the fun-supremacy
ご協力ありがとう モニター越しのサーカス
Thanks for your cooperation, a circus through the monitor
よろこんでくれたら それもめっちゃ上がるよ
If you're happy, that gets me super hyped too
キミのこと大好きだもん！
Because I love you so much!
ハイになって確信
Becoming high and certain,
混ぜるでもないよ思い
feelings that can't even be mixed,
レベル無限アップしちゃう?
leveling up infinitely?
ムテキナルポルカ サイキョウチックポルカ
Invincible Polka, Saikyoutic Polka!
喜んでくれたら そりゃもうめっさ上がるよ
If you're happy, my excitement shoots right up!
キミのこと大好きなもんだもん
Because I love you so much, you see!
ハイになって確信
Becoming high and certain,
混ぜるでもないよ思い
feelings that can't even be mixed,
レベル無限アップしちゃう?
leveling up infinitely?
ムテキナルポルカ サイキョウチックポルカ
Invincible Polka, Saikyoutic Polka!
Welcome!
やっぱりこれじゃないとポルカじゃないよね? 本当に本当にお待たせしました!
If it's not this, it wouldn't be Polka, right? Thank you so much for waiting!
愛嬌と笑顔がいのち 笑顔セカッシュに 最高に拡げちゃえ みんなで笑って It's showtime!
Charm and smiles are life, spreading smiles everywhere, everyone laughing together, It's showtime!
これから何が見たい? どんな時にもついてきてね!
What do you want to see next? Stay with me no matter what!
私は座長 尾丸ポルカ! もう名前は覚えてくれたかな?
I am the ringmaster, Omaru Polka! Have you memorized my name yet?
うん、ほんとにほんとにありがとう! 準備はいいですか?
Yep, truly, truly thank you! Are you ready?
Are You Ready?
さあさ違いのふれにおいで
Come on over to this extraordinary space,
きっと誰もが期待する 奇想天外なショウの始まりまりさ
where everyone expects an outlandish show to begin!
ずっと惹かれるでしょ? おっと危ないね
You'll be hooked forever, right? Woah, watch out,
それでは準備OKですか?
so is your preparation complete?
愉快な動物たち 玉の輪潜りで ドキドキハラハラの昨日いっさんでしょう
Cheerful animals leaping through hoops, heart-pounding and thrilling moments will be yesterday's news,
幕が上がるすぐさ 綱渡りにして ちょっくらのドジなんて可愛い許容?
the curtain rises instantly with tightrope walking, and a tiny blunder is cute and forgivable, right?
今宵は
tonight is...
Come on! Light up!
とっておきのライブ ぼうっとしないで もっともっと手をお高くこう!
This special live show, don't space out, put your hands up even higher!
ほらほらついておいで 目も回るようなサーカス きっとここだけだよ
Look, look, follow along, a dizzying circus, surely this is the only place,
ホログラムみたい キラキラ奇跡が踊る 巡る世界中をトリコにしちゃうぞ!
glittering miracles dance like a hologram, capturing the whole world!
今日のお目次はどうしようかな 屋根裏で秘密の作戦会議から始めるか
What's on today's agenda? Shall we start with a secret strategy meeting in the attic?
いっぱいの観客席を うわっと驚くような とびきりのショーを見せましょう
Let's show the packed audience a breathtaking, astonishing show!
思いついたらじっとしてられない ざわざき付いて Let's go!
Once we think of it, we can't stay still, buzz along, let's go!
あれがやりたい! これもやりたい!
I want to do that! I want to do this too!
どうして時間って足りないの?
Why is there never enough time?
はい! はい! はい! はい! お願いしまーす!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! Please!
今日は本当にありがとう! 最後まで楽しんでいってね! その手を強く伸ばして!
Thank you so much today! Enjoy it to the very end! Stretch out your hands strongly!
上手くいかなくって 空回ってばかりで 少し落ち込んじゃう日もあるけれど
When things don't go well and I'm just spinning my wheels, there are days when I feel a bit down, but
見ててね 大丈夫 いつまでも
watch over me, it'll be alright, forever and ever,
強くよしでなくなし 顔を上げて 今日のステージがほら
staying strong without fail, lift your face, look, today's stage,
待ってるのさ 最高にお祭り騒ぎ!
is waiting for us, the ultimate festival celebration!
アクセスようこそ朝昼夜もなく
Welcome, regardless of day or night!
会いに来てくれてうれしい
So glad you could come meet me!
わたしも実は待ってた
Actually, I was waiting too.
今日のあれこれキミと共有しておいて
Sharing today's events with you!
おかえりもいってきたけましも
Welcome back, come on in!
自由な時代だもん
It's a free-spirited era, right?
主張強めだった？
Got a strong presence?
意識高めだった？
Kept your standards high?
お天気次第とか冴えない言い訳より
No point blaming it on the weather or anything!
たのしい至上主義認めていきたい
I want to embrace the supreme fun of it all!
ご賛同ありがとうこれがわたしの流儀
Thanks for joining, this is how I roll!
カンチガイされたりそりゃまあ凹むよ
If you get a shortcut, of course you'll want to fall!
キミのことが好きだし（ペチャクチャポルカ）
I love you so much! (Pecha-kucha Polka!)
歩み寄ってにかにかむ
Stepping closer with a smile,
ちょっとした両想い？
A little mixed feeling?
ハートレベルアップしてしまう（ムテキなポルカ・サイキョウチックポルカ）
Our heart level is skyrocketing! (Muteki Polka, Saikyoutic Polka!)
こういう距離感今時っぽいのかな？
This distance feels so modern, doesn't it?
家族とか友達より近く感じることもあるし
Closer than family or friends,
急にご無沙汰する時があっても
Even if we suddenly go quiet,
いつだって戻ってこれる
We can always come right back.
あそびばっていいよね
It's fine to just play around!
一過性って言わないで
Don't call it a one-time thing,
永遠ってきかないで
Don't say it won't last forever.
自分たち次第未来も変えられる
We can change the future ourselves!
たのしい至上主義極めていくから
Let's aim for the ultimate fun supreme!
ご協力ありがとモニター越しのサーカス
Thanks for your help, a circus over the monitor!
よりそってくれたらそりゃもうめっちまアガるよ
If you join in, it gets so much more exciting!
キミのことが大好きだもん（トビバスポルカ）
I love you so much! (Tobibus Polka!)
ハイになって確信
Becoming "Hi!" with conviction,
まぎれもない両想い！
An unmistakable mutual feeling!
レベル無限アップしてしまう（ムテキなポルカ・サイキョウチックポルカ）
Leveling up to infinity! (Muteki Polka, Saikyoutic Polka!)
舞台 尾丸ポルカ ～あぁ素晴らしいアイドル人生かな～ 尾丸ポルカ2周年記念公演
[Title: Omaru Polka - Ah, What a Wonderful Idol Life - Omaru Polka 2nd Anniversary Commemoration Concert]
Fin.
月の光が映したエピローグ
An epilogue reflected in the moonlight,
静かに更ける夜に抱かれて
Embraced by the quiet, deepening night.
空に消えた白い息纏めた
A white breath faded away into the sky.
屋根裏のエピローグ
Roof-Attic Epilogue
作詞/作曲:OSTER project
Music / Lyrics: OSTER project
夢ような時間はいつもの一瞬の煌めきでも
Even if dreamlike moments last only a fleeting blink,
とても大切なことを思い出に残して
I'll keep those precious memories alive,
私を今日も温めてくれる
Warming me again today.
流れ星に詰め込んだ願い事
Wishes packed into shooting stars,
また明日笑顔で逢えますように
Hoping we can smile and meet again tomorrow.
閉じ上げた瞼の裏輝くあの景色抱いて
Holding close the scenery glowing behind closed eyelids,
今日は おやすみ
Today is time to rest.
待ち遠しい夢の続きを待ちきれない子供みたいに
Like a child too impatient for the continuation of a long-awaited dream,
降りた幕を背に見晴らした星空
I gaze at the starry sky with the dropped curtain behind.
明日も輝いていほしい
I hope it shines tomorrow too.
消えていく白熱灯
Fading incandescent lights,
眠りいく街並み
A townscape falling asleep.
愛しい終わりをこの目に映して
Reflecting this lovely ending before my eyes,
月明かりの差し込む屋根裏で
In the attic where moonlight streams in,
いくつもの場面数え微笑む
I count countless moments and smile.
ホログラムでできた夢でも
Even if it's a dream made in holograms,
確実に触れる思い出だから
It's a memory I can truly touch.
流れ星に詰め込んだ願い事
Wishes packed into shooting stars,
またここでみんなで逢えますように
Hoping we can meet here again.
繋がっていく夢の途中で
In the middle of a connecting dream,
未来への想いを持って
Holding thoughts for the future,
おやすみ
Good night.
待ち遠しい夢の続きを待ちきれない子供みたいに
Like a child too impatient for the continuation of a long-awaited dream,
降りた幕を背に見晴らした星空
I gazed as star-filled skies rained down.
明日も輝いていてほしい
I hope tomorrow shines just as bright.
消えていく白熱灯
Fading incandescent lights,
眠りいく街並み
A townscape falling asleep.
愛しい終わりのこの目に映して
Reflecting this lovely ending before my eyes,
月明かりの差すこ…
In the attic where moonlight streams in...
夢見る眠りで 幾つもの
In dreams and sleep, so many...
場面数え微笑む
Counting scenes and smiling.
ホログラム抱いた夢でも 確かめにさわれる想いでだから
Even in a hologram-embraced dream, let's make sure with touchable feelings.
流れ星に詰めた願い事が まだ心でみんなで眠るように繋がってく夢の途中で
Shooting stars packed with wishes, still sleeping together in our hearts, connecting on the way to a dream...
未来への想いを抱いて おやすみ
Holding feelings for the future, good night.
重大発表
[Major Announcement]
サイキョウチックポルカ
[Saikyouchic Polka]
アクセルお迎え 朝昼夜もなくて
Welcome to access, day or night,
会いに来てくれて嬉しい 私も実は待ってた
I'm so glad you came to see me, I was waiting too!
今日のあれこれ 君と共有して
Sharing today's this and that with you,
おかえりも いってきますも自由な時代だもんね
"Welcome back" and "See you" are free in this era!
主張強めだった？ 意識高めだった？
Was my assertion too strong? High awareness?
お天気しだいとか さえない言い訳より
Rather than weak excuses about the weather,
楽しい至上主義 認めていきたい
I want to embrace the supremacy of fun!
ご賛同ありがと これが私の流儀
Thanks for agreeing, that's my way of doing things.
勘違いされたら そりゃもう凹むよ
If I'm misunderstood, of course I'll feel down,
君のことが好きだし
because I like you!
歩み寄って はにかむ ちょっとした両想い？
Stepping closer, smiling shyly, a bit of mutual affection?
ハートレベルアップしちゃう
My heart level is going up!
（無敵なポルカ サイキョウチックポルカ）
(Invincible Polka, Saikyouchic Polka)
21:00 プレミア公開
[Premiering at 21:00]
監督 尾丸ポルカ
[Director: Omaru Polka]
主演 尾丸ポルカ
[Starring: Omaru Polka]
あー、どこだっけ？ ちょっと待って...
Ah, where was it? Wait a second...
違うな、絶対えっと... もう一回いきます！
No, definitely um... Let's go again!
最後！もうステージは始まってんだぜ！あれ？
The last one! The stage has already started! Huh?
ってサイリウムを... ってすんごい分かる？
Like, the penlights... You know that feeling?
ちゃんと、ちゃんとこう... 大丈夫？
Properly, properly like... Are you okay?
チャンネル登録者数100万人 ありがとう！！！
My channel's reached 1 million subscribers! THANK YOU!!!
おまる座のみんな
To everyone in Omaru-za, thank you!
みなさま、今回は、おまるポルカ2周年配信の最後まで...
Everyone, thank you for staying until the end of Omaru Polka's 2nd anniversary stream...
来てくださって、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you so very much for coming.
おまるポルカです。
It's Omaru Polka!
てことで、今回も2周年を記念して...
And so, for my 2nd anniversary...
グッズを作りました!なん...て?
I've made some merch! Guess what?
てことで、今回も2周年を記念してグッズを作りました!今回はポルカが「まあいいな」って思ったものを本当に本当に詰め込みに詰め込ませていただきました!こちらです!どうぞ!どん!
Here it is! Tada!
活動2周年フルセットはキャンバスアートとブロマイドセット、おまるざはっぴの3点セット!
The 2nd Anniversary Full Set includes...
2周年公演記念キャンバスアートは久賀フーナ先生描き下ろしの素敵なキャンバスアートになっております!はい、次。
A lovely canvas art illustrated by Kugafooda-sensei!
ついに、おまるポルカ1st EP『Welcome to POLKA!』が出ます!
My 1st EP, "Welcome to POLKA!!" will be released!
今回の配信で歌った楽曲が詰まりに詰まっております!ついに出せて本当に嬉しいです!
It's packed with songs I've sung on my streams so far.
こちら皆さん買って部屋に飾ったり聴いていただけるととっても嬉しいです!もうジャケットとかもめちゃくちゃかっこいいもう赤って本当に気持ちが高まるよね。
Everyone, I'd be so happy if you could play it in your rooms or listen to it.
今日歌った歌もほぼほぼ入ってます。
Today's songs are almost all on there!
ありがとうございます。次!
Thank you so much! Next!
2周年公演記念ブロマイドセットは、あら可愛い。2Lサイズ127×178mm、3枚のブロマイドがセットになっております。あら可愛い。どれも魅力的なポルカですね。
The 2nd Anniversary Bromide Set features 3 2L-size bromides!
そして、おまるざはっぴではっぴ!いやこれね、ポルカ本当にマジでデザイン凝ってて、ライブとか配信に来てもらいたいし、見てもらいたいんだよね!
And here is the "Omaru-za Happi"!
すごい背中が、あのシンポとか書いてる。もうだからお揃いなんだよ。もう
It even has "Sympo" written on the back!
これもね、そばえがね、すごくいいものにしたくてめちゃくちゃ運営さんと一生懸命相談しました。多ぶん、君たちが一番来て、「あ、いいものだな」って思えるものになっております!最高!
This happi is such a great item, so I consulted with the production team!
さらに、2周年フルセット購入には、なんと!おまるポルカからの複製手書きおと手紙と、特典ボイス、2人きりのアンコールがついてくる!
And the Full Set includes a replica handwritten letter and voice drama!
あんな夢をね、買ってくれた人にしか言えないんだけどさ、手紙とかもめちゃくちゃおまるぽるかまで綴ってまあね、これね、この前もやったんですけど、すごく好評に
You can only get the letter if you buy the set!
またね、ちょっとね、もう1枚分のお手紙ビッシリって感じでなかに込めたので読んでもらえると嬉しいです!買ってね、確かめて、プレト、嬉しい!
Every single letter was hand-filled, so I'd be so happy if you grab one!
そして、特典ボイスは、うーん、2人きりのアンコールね?うん、なるほど、2人きりのアンコール。2人きりのアンコール、うーん、舞台の終わりの家庭の中かな?そこで、うーん、まあ分かるやろ!なのでぜひぜひフルセット御検討お買い求めいただけると幸いです!
And as for the voice drama, well... you'll see!
もちろんグッズ単品でもお買い求めいただけますのでご安心を。詳しくはホロライブ公式ホームページをチェックしてみてください。たくさんのご安心を。
Of course, you can buy items individually, so please check Hololive's official page!
そして続きまして楽曲リリース情報です!だーん!
And now, release info for the 1st original song!
おまるポルカオリジナル楽曲3週連続配信第1弾として『サイキョウチックポルカ』がこのあと0時から配信となります!
"Saikyo Chick Polka" releases right at midnight!
作曲は田中秀和、作詞はこだまさおりさんにお願いいたしました!本当にありがとうございます。
Music by Tanaka Hidekazu, lyrics by Kodama Saori!
才能、皆はわかるかな?ポルカが本当に本当に作ってもらいたかった夢をこちら叶えられました!この後21時からはこちらもすごく手のかかったMVが公開される予定ですので、こちらもまた見に来てください!
I really hope you love it, and the MV premieres at 21:00!
そして第2弾となる8月24日、こちらも0時、8月23日日は24時ですね。から『屋根裏のエピローグ』
Then for the 2nd song on August 23rd: "Yaneura no Epilogue"!
今日歌ったのすごくかっこいいだろう。あれも配信されて、後日MVも配信されて。
Both the song and MV will be released then!
そして第3弾、8月31日0時、8月30日は、8月31日は24時かな。はい。よいよ「ホログラムサーカス」配信となりました!
And the 3rd song on August 31st: "Hologram Circus"!
ありがとうございます!こちらもぜひチェックしておいてください。
Please check that out too!
ポルカの、ええ、全5話は以上にポル、誰から、誰から伝言をされて。おまるかの、ええと、委託は以上になります。本当に今日は公演に来てくださってありがとうございました。
Thank you so much for coming to the concert today!
足元のお悪い中ね来てくださって、見てくださってありがとうございました。あ、天気か?天気だったかもしれないな。
Thank you for visiting us through all kinds of weather!
はい。というわけで、来年、再来年とまたのお越しを心よりお待ちしております。急に訪さっとする時があっても、いつだって戻ってこれる遊び場だっていいよね。
We look forward to seeing you again next year and the year after!
アイドルに笑顔なんて要らない。
そんな世界は要らない。
Idols don't need smiles.
We don't need a world like that.
舞台 尾丸ポルカ あゝ、素晴らしきアイドル人生かな
Stage: Omaru Polka - Ah, What a Wonderful Idol Life